Mobolaji Stephanie Babalola

07375667923 | stephanie.babalola99@gmail.com

PROFILE

Mobolaji is a passionate Mechanical Engineer who graduated in July 2023. She has experience and knowledge using various tools such as AutoCAD and Python. Her passion for engineering is shown through continual engagement as a student member with IMechE and mentoring prospective engineering students. In addition to her excellent academic record she has several years of engineering achievement with leading employers and other employment experience showing her determination and application. Mobolaji is currently searching for a graduate training and development role that will allow her to use her programming knowledge and mechanical skills to work with a team to deliver tangible and useful solutions.

EDUCATION

University of Portsmouth

(September 2019 - June 2023)

• BEng (Hons) Mechanical Engineering (1st Class)

IET and IMechE Accredited Degree

Brockenhurst College

(September 2015 – June 2017)

- BTEC Level 3 90 Credit Diploma in Engineering
- AS Level in Mathematics, Physics, Product Design, and Chemistry

Marlborough Science Academy

(October 2011 – June 2015)

11 GCSEs including Mathematics, English, Physics, French and Engineering

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Props & Set Designer at Theatre Peckham

(April 2024 – Present)

- Design and create captivating sets and props that bring the vision of the production to life.
- Collaborate closely with the production team to understand the artistic vision and requirements of each show.
- Source and acquire materials, furniture, and props needed for the production within the allocated budget.
- Ensure the timely and efficient installation and maintenance of sets and props throughout the duration of the production.

Graduate Mechanical Engineer

at Ferrovial

(September 2023 – Present)

- Assisting in coordination of team activities to ensure that projects are completed on budget and on time.
- Working with the procurement team to ensure compliance with financial parameters.
- Assisting in ensuring the project complies with health, safety, environmental and quality requirements.
- Assisting Project Manager on the management of the team, giving advice on appropriate sourcing levels, effective performance management, employee development and motivation

Administrative Assistant

at Ashbourne Estate Agents

(November 2021 – June 2023)

- Creating and allocating reactive maintenance jobs for over 200 properties.
- Processing invoice payments for work orders and liaising directly with contractors.
- Utilising Excel and STATS software to process commission payments for property managers.
- Answering calls from prospective tenants and scheduling viewings.

Freelance Mechanical & Electrical Engineer with Clive Kavan

(September 2017 – September 2019)

- Carried out preventive and reactive maintenance tasks and in doing so gained proficiency with soldering, parts assembly and wood working (measuring, sawing, chiselling)
- Organised stock and equipment as well as sourced parts around the country
- Built mixing desks at music recording studios as well as reinstalled capacitors and several other electrical components

Asset Management Apprentice at Gatwick Airport

(July 2017 – March 2018)

- Produced weekly resource reports using Microsoft Excel for engineering management team
- Attended meetings with contractors to discuss asset performance and recommend corrective maintenance
- Organised area inspections by analysing technical drawings and allocated inspections across engineering department
- Shadowed engineers across baggage, fire safety and shuttle maintenance departments
- Presented weekly summary of achievements to Head of Engineering and Apprenticeship Manager
- Participated in regular health and safety assessments

Junior Technician at Elstree Precision

(*January* 2017 – *February* 2017)

- Operated lathes, CNC milling machines and angle grinders for machining material according to customer specification
- Stocked and organised materials and tool pieces in storage
- Assisted technicians in the daily upkeep of all manufacturing equipment

Junior Technician at Aeroflex Engineering

(July 2016 - August 2016)

- Assisted with inventory and kept track of tools and materials in storage
- Communicated with technicians across departments to provide reactive maintenance when needed
- Assisted technicians in the daily upkeep of all production equipment on the shop floor.
- Health and safety

CODING SKILLS

- Languages
 - Python
 - o MATLAB
 - JavaScript
 - o HTML
 - o CSS
 - o React
 - Node.js
 - o Vue.js
 - o Babel.js
- Platforms
 - o Visual Studio Code
 - o Github
 - Postman
 - MongoDB Atlas
 - Microsoft Azure

LANGUAGE SKILLS

- French Language B1 Proficiency
- Yoruba Language B1 Proficiency
- Spanish Language A1 Proficiency

INTERESTS & HOBBIES

- Fashion and styling
- Reading crime fiction and romance novels
- Music playing guitar and attending live music performances
- Networking
 - o Social Events Coordinator & Publicity Officer for the IMechE Young Members Panel
 - Member of BGIT (Black Girls in Tech)
 - Member of AFBE (Association for BME (Black and Minority Ethnic) Engineers)
 - Member of WeleaP (Women Leaders in Aerospace and Mechanical Engineering Programs)